bodybuilders.com 2017-12-31

# Bodybuilding.com Help: What Is Your Privacy Policy?

Customer Support

1-208-377-9994 | International

### What is your privacy policy?

**Last Modified: October 26, 2016**

At Bodybuilding.com, we want you to know how we collect, use, share, and protect information about you. By interacting with Bodybuilding.com through our website and mobile applications, you consent to the use of information that is collected or submitted as described in this Privacy Policy.

We may change or add to this Privacy Policy, so we encourage you to review it periodically. By using this site or application, you agree to the collection, use, and transfer of your data as described in this Privacy Policy. We may collect your personal information from, transfer it to, and store and process it in the United States and other countries outside of where you live. If you do not want your information to be collected, used, and transferred as described by this policy, you may revoke your consent to our Privacy Policy. To revoke your consent, please e-mail [webmaster@bodybuilding.com](mailto:webmaster@bodybuilding.com). If you revoke your consent, your account and profile information will be removed from our website.

Information collected on our sites and applications is stored in the United States; therefore, your information may become subject to U.S. law. By using our website or mobile applications, you consent to the transfer of your data overseas and across borders, and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. The laws governing data in your home country may differ from those in the countries to which data is transferred. By accessing and using our website and mobile applications, you consent to the transfer of your data in this manner.

**Scope of this Policy**

This policy applies to information we collect or use on sites and applications owned or controlled by Bodybuilding.com, LLC or its affiliates (“Bodybuilding.com”). This policy applies to all of the services offered by Bodybuilding.com and its affiliates, including services Bodybuilding.com provides on mobile devices.

Our Privacy Policy does not apply to services offered by other companies or individuals, including products or sites linked from our services. Our Privacy Policy does not cover the information practices of other companies and organizations who advertise our services, and who may use cookies, pixel tags, and other technologies to serve and offer relevant ads.

**Bodybuilding.com and the EU – U.S. Privacy Shield**

Bodybuilding.com complies with the EU – U.S. Privacy Shield Framework for personal information transferred to the United State from users in the EU. Under the Framework, Bodybuilding.com is subject to the Federal Trade Commission’s enforcement powers. Bodybuilding.com complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. Bodybuilding.com has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

In compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles, Bodybuilding.com commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Bodybuilding.com at [legal@bodybuilding.com](mailto:legal@bodybuilding.com).

Bodybuilding.com has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles to BBB EU Privacy Shield, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit <https://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/> for more information and to file a complaint.

Finally and in [certain circumstances](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction), EU individuals may also have the right to invoke binding arbitration before the Privacy Shield Panel. Please see <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=C-Pre-Arbitration-Requirements> for more information on the binding arbitration option.

**Our Technology**

**What are cookies?** A cookie is a small text file stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. There are two types of cookies: 

  * Session cookies are used to make it easier for you to navigate on websites. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser.
  * Persistent cookies are used to run our technology as they enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our websites. Persistent cookies remain on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following the directions provided in your internet browser's 'help' file.

**What are pixel tags?** A pixel tag (also commonly known as a web beacon) is a type of technology placed on a website or within the body of an e-mail for the purpose of tracking activity on websites, or when e-mails are opened or accessed, and is often used in combination with cookies.

**Other Environments (mobile applications)**

In environments that do not support cookies, such as mobile applications, we may use other similar technologies for the same purpose of cookies. To serve our ads in mobile applications we collect identifiers, such as a Google Advertising ID or Apple IDFA, depending on the operating system of your mobile device.

**Linking Environments**

To serve you our personalized advertisements and provide a seamless online experience, we may link your identifiers on the different environments you are using. At no point do we collect identifying personal data such as your name or address to operate the linking.

**Information We Collect**

Bodybuilding.com collects information to provide better services to our valued users. We collect information in the following ways: 

  * **Information you give us.** For example, Bodybuilding.com collects personal information when you create an account with Bodybuilding.com; when you place an order; when you enter promotions or sweepstakes, such as your name, email address, birth date, gender, and ZIP code; and when you use our online forum.
  * **Information we get from your use of our services.** We collect information about the services that you use and how you use them, such as information about how you use our sites and mobile applications, visit a website that uses our advertising services, view or interact with our ads and content, and information about your computer or mobile device. This information may include: 
    * **Device Information**  
We collect device-specific information such as your hardware model, operating system version, unique device identifiers, and mobile network information including your phone number. Bodybuilding.com may associate your device identifiers or phone number with your Bodybuilding.com account.

    * **Log Information**  
When you use our services or view content provided by Bodybuilding.com, we automatically collect and store certain information in our server logs. This includes: 
      * details of how you use our services (e.g., your search queries).
      * IP address
      * device event information such as crashes, system activity, hardware setting, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request, and referral URL
      * cookies that may uniquely identify your browser on your Bodybuilding.com account

    * **Location Information**  
When you use Bodybuilding.com services, we may collect and process information about your actual location. We use various technologies to determines location, including your IP address, GPS, and other sensors that may, for example, provide Bodybuilding.com with information on nearby devices, Wi-Fi access points, and cell towers.

If you have downloaded one or more of our mobile applications, you may have the option to opt-in to location sharing for additional application capabilities. We may use this information to provide you with location-based services, such as advertising, search results, and other personalized content. Most mobile devices allow you to turn off location services. Most likely, these controls are located in the devices’ settings menu; however, if you have questions about how to disable your device’s location services, we recommend you contact your mobile service carrier or your device manufacturer.

    * **Unique Application Numbers**  
Certain services include a unique application number. This number and information about your installation may be sent to Bodybuilding.com when you install or uninstall a certain service or when a service periodically contacts our servers, such as for updates.

    * **Local Storage**  
Bodybuilding.com may collect and store information – including personal information – locally on your device using mechanisms such as browser web storage and application data caches.

    * **Cookies and Similar Technologies**  
Bodybuilding.com may set and access cookies on your computer. We may also set and access device identifiers which may include your IP address, user agent information (e.g., browser version, OS type, and version), and device-provided identifiers. Once you interact with our services, site(s), and/or application(s), Bodybuilding.com may recognize your device to provide you with a personalized experience, independent of your device settings.

Bodybuilding.com lets other trusted business use cookies or similar technologies for advertising and research purposes on our services. This information is used to serve ads for Bodybuilding.com products or services or for the products or services of other companies when you visit this website or other websites. These companies use non-personally-identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over, hardware/software information, cookie and session ID) and personally identifiable information (e.g., static IP address) during your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These parties typically use a cookie, web beacon, or other similar tracking technologies to collect this information. Other companies’ use of their cookies and device identifiers is subject to their own privacy policies, not this one. Advertisers or other companies do not have access to Bodybuilding.com’s cookies. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, visit <http://networkadvertising.org/>.

Bodybuilding.com uses web beacons to access Bodybuilding.com cookies inside and outside our network of websites and in connection with Bodybuilding.com products and services.

    * **E-mail Communications**  
To help us make e-mails more useful and interesting, we often receive a confirmation when you open e-mail from Bodybuilding.com or its affiliates if your computer supports such capabilities.

  * **Social Media.** Bodybuilding.com engages with guests on multiple social media platforms (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, and Pinterest). If you contact us on ore of our social media platforms, we may contact you via direct message. In these instances, your interactions with us are governed by this privacy policy as well as the privacy policy of the social media platform you use.
    * **Social Media Widgets**  
Our sites and mobile applications include social media features, such as the Facebook “Like” button, Google Plus, Pinterest, and Twitter widgets. These features may collect information about your IP address and which page you’re visiting on our site, and they may set a cookie or employ other tracking technologies. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with those features are governed by the privacy policies of the companies that provide them.

**Cookies, Tracking, and Interest-Based Advertising**

The "help" function of your browser should contain instructions on how to set your computer to accept all cookies, to notify you when a cookie is issued, or to not receive cookies at any time. If you set your device to not receive cookies at any time, certain personalized services cannot be provided to you, and accordingly, you may not be able to take full advantage of all of our features.

**Third-Party Advertisers and Links to Other Websites**

Our site includes third-party interest-based advertising using information you make available to us when you interact with our sites, content, or services. Interest-based ads are displayed to you based on information from activities such as purchasing on our sites, visiting sites that contain Bodybuilding.com content or ads, or interacting with Bodybuilding.com tools.

**How is Your Information Used?**

Examples of how we use the information we collect include:

  * **Product and Service Fulfillment**
    * Fulfill and manage purchases, orders, payments, and returns/exchanges
    * Respond to requests for information about our products and services on our website, mobile website, or mobile applications, or to otherwise serve you
    * Connect with you regarding customer service via our contact center or social media platforms
    * Administer sweepstakes and contests
    * Allow you to, via our website or mobile applications, sign up for our e-mail newsletter, search for products and check availability, check prices, provide product ratings and reviews, track your orders, update account information, etc.
  * **Our Marketing Purposes**
    * Deliver coupons and promotions, newsletters, e-mails, mobile messages, and social media notifications
    * Provide interactive features on the website or mobile applications, such as product reviews or weekly deals, send marketing communications and other information regarding, products, services, and promotions
    * Administer contests, sweepstakes, promotions, surveys, etc.
  * **Internal Operations**
    * Improve the effectiveness of our website, stores, mobile experience, and marketing efforts
    * Conduct research and analysis, including surveys
    * Perform other business activities as needed
  * **Legal Compliance**
    * For example, assist law enforcement and respond to legal/regulatory inquiries

**Information We Share**

We do not share personal information with companies, organizations, and individuals outside of Bodybuilding.com unless one of the following circumstances applies:

  * **With Your Consent:** We will share personal information with companies, organizations, or individuals outside of Bodybuilding.com when we have your consent to do so. For example, if you create a BodySpace account and elect to make it available to the public or you publicly comment on our forum, your information will be accessible on our website, mobile, or social applications.
  * For External Processing: We provide personal information to our affiliates or other trusted businesses or persons to process it for us, based on our instructions and in compliance with our Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.
  * Service Providers: We may share the information we collect with companies that provide support services to us (such as e-mail providers, mobile marketing services, analytics providers, web hosting providers, call center/chat providers, sweepstakes vendors, payment processors, data enhancement services, or fraud prevention providers) or that help us market our products and services. These companies may need information about you in order to perform their functions.
  * For Legal Reasons: We will share personal information with companies, organizations, or individuals outside of Bodybuilding.com if we have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation, or disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to: 
    * meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process, or enforceable governmental request.
    * enforce applicable Terms of Use, including investigation of potential violations.
    * detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues.
    * protect against harm to the rights, property, or safety of Bodybuilding.com, our users, or the public as required or permitted by law.

This does not include selling, renting, sharing, or otherwise disclosing personally identifiable information from customers for commercial purposes.

If Bodybuilding.com undergoes a merger, corporate reorganization, acquisition, or asset sale, your personal data may be shared. If you do not want us to share your personal data in these manners, please do not provide it to us.

Please note that Bodybuilding.com may be required to release an individual’s personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities in order to meet national security and/or law enforcement requirements.

In the context of an onward transfer, Bodybuilding.com has responsibility for the processing of personal information it receives under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Bodybuilding.com shall remain liable under the Principles if its agent processes such personal information in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless the organization proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

**Accessing and Updating Your Personal Information**

Bodybuilding.com acknowledges the individual’s right to access their personal data. Whenever you use our services, we aim to provide you with access to your personal information. If that information is wrong, we strive to give you ways to update it quickly or to delete it – unless we have to keep that information for legitimate business or legal purposes. When updating your personal information, we may ask you to verify your identity before we can act on your request.

We may reject requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort (for example, developing a new system or fundamentally changing an existing practice), risk the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup systems).

Where we can provide information access and correction, we will do so for free, except where it would require a disproportionate effort. We aim to maintain our services in a manner that protects information from accidental or malicious destruction. Because of this, after you delete information from our services, we may not immediately delete residual copies from our active servers and may not remove information from our backup systems.

You have the right to request information about the personal data we hold on you. If your data is incorrect, incomplete, or irrelevant you can ask to have the information corrected or removed. To access or update your personal information e-mail webmaster@bodybuilding.com or call 1-866- 236-8417 with your current contact information and the personal information you would like to access. We will provide you the personal information requested if reasonably available, or will describe the types of personal information we typically collect.

**E-mail Opt-out**

We communicate with users who subscribe to our services on a regular basis via e-mail. For example, we may use your e-mail address to confirm your request, to send you notice of payments, to send you information about changes to our products and services, and to send notices and other disclosures as required by law. Generally, users cannot opt-out of these communications, but they will be primarily informational in nature rather than promotional.

However, we provide you the opportunity to exercise an opt-out choice if you do not want to receive other types of communication from us, such as emails or updates from us regarding new services and products offered on the Sites. The opt-out choice may be exercised by ticking or unticking the appropriate box if such checkbox is available at the points where personal data is collected or by contacting us. We will process your unsubscribe request as soon as possible, but please be aware that in some circumstances you may receive a few more messages until the unsubscribe is processed. You also may opt-out of receiving such emails by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link within the text of the email.

**Mobile**

  * **Push Notifications:** You may at any time opt-out from further allowing Bodybuilding.com to send you push notifications by adjusting the notification permissions in the Settings on your mobile device.
  * **Geo-location:** You may at any time opt-out from further allowing Bodybuilding.com to access location data by adjusting the permission in your mobile device.

**How is Your Personal Information Protected?**

**Security Methods:** We maintain administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to protect your personal information. When we collect or transmit sensitive information, we use industry standard methods to protect that information. However, no e-commerce solution, website, mobile application, database, or system is completely secure or “hacker proof.” You are also responsible for taking reasonable steps to protect your personal information against unauthorized disclosure or misuse.

**E-mail Security:** “Phishing” is a scam designed to steal your personal information. If you receive an e-mail that looks like it is from us asking for your personal information, do not respond. We will never request your password, username, credit card information, or other personal information through e-mail.

**Children’s Personal Information:** We recognize the particular importance of protecting privacy where children are involved. We do not knowingly collect personal information online form children under the age of 13. If a child under the age of 13 has provided us with personal information online, we ask that a parent or guardian e-mail [legal@bodybuilding.com](mailto:legal@bodybuilding.com) or call 1-866-236-8417.

**California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our visitors who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal data to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us at [legal@bodybuilding.com](mailto:legal@bodybuilding.com). For all requests, you must include your full name, street address, city, state, and zip code. We will not accept requests via telephone, postal mail, or facsimile, and we are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent property, or that do not have complete information.

* * *

## Other Topics

1-866-236-8417

1-208-377-9994 | International

## Help Index

Contact Information |  Gift Certificates |  Order Changes |  Payment Methods  
---|---|---|---  
Shipping Information |  Returns & Exchanges |  Account Management |  BodySpace Assistance  
Inventory Management |  Privacy & Security |  All Access |  Free Shipping Details
